randmcnally.com 2019-12-09

# Rand McNally | Privacy Policy

* * *

##### Last Updated: October 22, 2019

By using this web site, you agree to the following policy:

This is the Privacy Policy for RM Acquisition, LLC. d/b/a Rand McNally ("Rand McNally")

Shopping and obtaining information on-line has changed our lives. At Rand McNally, your trust and satisfaction is of the utmost importance. Because we respect your privacy, we have instituted policies intended to ensure that your personal information is handled in a safe and responsible manner.

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through Rand McNally's websites. We suggest that you review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may update it from time to time. 

  * What information do we collect?
  * How do we use your information?
  * Third party merchants "Presented by Rand McNally"
  * How do you know your information is secure?
  * Children's Privacy
  * How can you update your information?
  * Changes to this Privacy Policy Statement
  * Conflict in terms
  * Product specific policies
  * Additional information and how to contact us

### What information do we collect?

Every time you visit a Rand McNally website, our Web server automatically collects the following non-personally identifiable information: your Internet service provider's address, the referring URL, pixel tags, information on the pages you access on our website, and other technologies, and aggregated, demographic, and other information specifically provided by you.  Except where required by law, Rand McNally may use non-personally identifiable information for any purpose.  For instances in which Rand McNally is required by law to protect non-personally identifiable information as if it were personally identifiable information then we may only use it as we use personally identifiable information.  Were non-personally identifiable information is combined with personally identifiable information then we will protect all the information as personally identifiable information.

We also collect personally identifiable information that you provide, such as survey information and information you provide when you make a purchase for a product or service, register your e-mail address, register a product or software or sign-up for sweepstakes or contests. If you register for our Rand McNally Classroom products and services, we will also ask you to provide your school or organization's name, school district, type of institution, enrollment and your position with that institution. If you have visited our website before and provided us with your email address, we collect information on what pages you access or visit while on our website.

When you make a purchase on a Rand McNally website, we ask you for your full name, billing address, telephone number, email address, and credit card information. If you want your order shipped to someone other than yourself, you will need to provide us the name and address of the recipient.

We use a cookie to help us determine repeat visits to our websites. This cookie may be assigned to any user of our websites. This cookie does not contain any personally identifiable information, and simply helps us better understand if we are providing services that are valuable to our users. If you delete our cookie but have selected "remember me" in your profile, we will give you a new cookie the next time you log in. If you use our Maps & Directions features, we may store this information in a cookie to allow you to more easily re-use this information. Even without using cookies, you will be able to take advantage of almost all of the features on our websites.

We also collect information through our Analytics tracking code to support Display Advertising by Google Analytics, which collects data about our websites’ traffic via the DoubleClick cookie.

return to top

### How do we use your information?

The information we collect is used:

  * to generally improve the content and layout of our website
  * to improve the content and layout of our website for individual visitors
  * to notify you about updates to our website
  * to contact you for marketing purposes
  * in some instances, shared with our parent company and affiliates (the **Rand McNally Affiliates** ) or other organizations for marketing purposes
  * for internal review
  * for Display Advertising by Google Analytics

When you supply us with personal information to request a catalog or order a product, the information you provide will be added to our customer file (including your name, address, phone number and e-mail address). You may receive periodic mailings, emails, or telephone contact from us with information on new products and services, discounts, special promotions or upcoming events that we offer. If you do not want to receive such mailings from Rand McNally, then please  Click Here for information on where to reach us to remove yourself from our contact list.

We may send you e-mail with information on new products and services, discounts, special promotions or upcoming events that are being offered. If you do not wish to receive such e-mail from us in the future, please Click Here for information on where to contact us to remove yourself from our email list or, click on the "opt-out" link on any e-mail you receive from us. Please note that when you make a purchase and provide us with your e-mail address, we may send you confirmation of your order via e-mail even if you have chosen not to receive future email from us about our products and services. We may also contact you by mail or telephone if we have questions about your order.

We may supply our customer file (including your name, address, phone number and e-mail address) to certain Rand McNally Affiliates. In addition to information provided to Rand McNally Affiliates, we may also provide your name, address and phone number (but not your e-mail address) to a select group of companies who are not Rand McNally Affiliates and whose products you may find of interest. If you do not want us to share this information with these companies, we can put you on our "do-not-share" or "do not call" lists. Please Click Here for information on where to contact us if you do not want us to share this information with Rand McNally Affiliates or other third parties.

Note that Rand McNally Affiliates and other third parties with whom we share your information have their own privacy statements, and those statements apply to your personal information when it is held by such Rand McNally Affiliates or third parties. Please refer to the Rand McNally Affiliate or third party privacy statements, as applicable, for further information on how those entities treat your personal information.

In some instances, we use third party companies to help us in providing our products and services to you, to assist us in managing customer information, to fulfill promotions and to communicate with you. Some of these third party service providers are given access to some or all of the information you provide to us, including your e-mail address, and may use cookies on our behalf. These third party service providers are contractually restricted from using your information in any manner, other than in helping us to provide you with the products and services available from Rand McNally.

Rand McNally may participate with certain reputable companies who offer you the ability to establish a membership that would enable you to participate in travel and entertainment programs. 

We may share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when: (1) permitted or required by law; or, (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions; or, (3) investigating fraud which has already taken place. The information is not provided to these companies for marketing purposes.

We may buy or sell business assets or be acquired by or acquire other companies. In such transactions, personal information generally is one of the transferred business assets. In addition, in the event that we merge or consolidate with another entity or there is a change in control of Rand McNally, or, if all or substantially all of the assets of Rand McNally are sold to a third party, we may transfer your personal information to the third party. This information may include your name, mailing address and email address among other information. Please know that if such a transfer takes place, the third party acquiring the information will be advised of your preferences about how we use your information. After the transfer takes place, use of your information is subject to the privacy statement of the third party that acquires it. You should check that company's privacy statement for information on how it will use your customer information.

We have implemented Google Analytics features based on Display Advertising, which may include Remarketing, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, the DoubleClick Campaign Manager integration, or Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting.  We may use Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online through third party vendors, including Google, which may display our ads on websites throughout the internet.  Rand McNally and third party vendors, including Google, may use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve advertisements based on your past visits to our websites, and to report our ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services as it relates to visits to Rand McNally websites.  We may use data from Google’s Interest-based advertising or third party audience data (such as age, gender, and interests) with Google Analytics to, among other things, better provide you with appropriate content.

By using the [Ads Setting](https://www.google.com/settings/ads), you can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads.Please also consult Google Analytics’ [currently available opt-outs](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/), and Google Analytics’ safeguarding your data webpage (www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html).

return to top

### Third party merchants "Presented by Rand McNally"

If you make a purchase from a merchant site with a link originating from the Rand McNally website or a merchant catalog or website "presented by" Rand McNally, the information you provide to that merchant, such as your credit card number and contact information, is provided to the merchant and not to Rand McNally. Providing this information to the merchant enables the transaction to take place. However, you should know that the merchant may, if you do not advise them to the contrary, share your name and postal and email addresses with third parties, including Rand McNally. You should also know that these merchants have their own privacy and data collection practices and are not covered by the Rand McNally Privacy Policy Statement.

Merchants on the Rand McNally website and those merchants, who send catalogs or host websites "presented by" Rand McNally, have separate privacy and data collection practices. We have no control over and therefore no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. For more information regarding merchants appearing on randmcnally.com or other merchants who send catalogs or host websites "presented by" Rand McNally and their privacy policies, please see the merchant's home page and click on their Information link or review the customer service section of any catalog you may receive from the merchant.

Merchants that have links on the Rand McNally website may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of these merchants are not covered by the Rand McNally Privacy Policy Statement.

return to top

### How do you know your information is secure?

When you see either a solid key icon or a locked padlock icon at the lower portion of your browser window, then your site is secured through Secure Sockets Layer. We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving your information on our website. If you do not see one of these icons, please contact your Internet service provider. When we transfer and receive certain types of sensitive information, such as financial information, we will redirect you to a secure server and notify you through a pop-up screen on our website.

We have appropriate security measures in place in our facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our website so you can feel comfortable and secure.

Please note that e-mail is not encrypted and is not considered a secure means of transmitting credit card numbers.

return to top

### Children's Privacy

Rand McNally does not seek to solicit information from anyone under the age of thirteen (a "Child"). If a Child submits information to us through any part of our website, and we know that the person submitting the information is a Child, we delete the information as soon as we discover it and do not use it for any purpose, nor do we disclose it to third parties. If your child has submitted personal information to us and you would like to request that such information be removed from our customer lists, you may contact us using the contact us information listed below, and we will honor your request.

While our Rand McNally Classroom product is for use specifically by students, any usage of the product is allowed only with a single, generic, school access password. We only count the number of users by school. No personal information is collected or stored by Rand McNally on student usage of the Classroom services.

return to top

### How can you update your information?

We will provide you access to the following information if you send us an e-mail, call us or write to us:

  * financial information (such as your credit card account information)
  * unique identifier information (your customer number or password)
  * transaction information (dates on which you made purchases, amounts and types of purchases)
  * contact information (your name, address, phone number)

We will evaluate each request and reply in an appropriate manner and form of communication that respects the security of the information you have requested. Click Here for Contact Information.

return to top

### Changes to this Privacy Policy Statement

From time to time, we may use the information you provide us for new, unanticipated uses not previously addressed in our Privacy Policy Statement. If our information practices change at some time in the future, we will post the policy changes on the privacy page of our website to notify you of these changes, and the revised Privacy Policy Statement will apply to all of your personal information that we have on file, provided, however, that we will continue to honor any past requests not to share your information with third parties. You should check our website periodically for more information on how we use the data we collect.

If there is a material change in the manner we use data we collect, we will update this Privacy Policy Statement to reflect these changes.

return to top

### Conflict in terms

It is our goal to make our privacy practices easy to understand. We have created this easy-to-read Privacy Policy Statement with that goal in mind. Some browsers utilize privacy enhancing technology to translate our Privacy Policy Statement into a computer readable format. The technology then requires that the computer format be translated back into human readable format for you to read. This translation back into human readable format is often referred to as a "Policy Summary". It is possible that through these translations, the Policy Summary may unintentionally end up being inconsistent with the Privacy Policy Statement upon which it is based. It might fail to address an issue or it might address an issue not raised in our Privacy Policy Statement. For this reason, you should rely on our Privacy Policy Statement as the most accurate and definitive description of our practices.

return to top

### Product specific policies

return to top

### Additional information and how to contact us

For your convenience, our website contains links to a wide variety of other websites. We do not control how these other websites gather and use information about their users. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of all websites you link to from our website.

If you have any comments or questions about our Privacy Policy Statement, please feel free to contact us at:

### Rand McNally Consumer Affairs

P.O. Box 7600  
Chicago, IL 60680-9915

Special Note: When you contact us, please provide us with your exact name and address as it appears on correspondence you have received from us.
